Guide to the Arnie Goldwag Brooklyn Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) collection ARC.002
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 1: Subject Files, 1950-2007; 7.25 Linear feet
  - Freedom Ride - Rallies, Film, Etc. and Freedom Highways, 1961-1962, 1965, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cambridge, Maryland [Segregated Facilities], 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - KKK - WCC - PAT, Etc., 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - House UnAmerican Activities Committee - Activities, Etc. (HUAC), circa 1961-1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Demonstrations - Philadelphia [Chester]; N.J., 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Birmingham, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Christmas Buying Boycott, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bill Moore [Murder], Freedom March, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - [March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom], 1963, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - March on Washington (Aug 20, 1963), Also Walk Brooklyn - DC, 1963-1964, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - [March on Washington, photocopies of 1963 documents], circa 2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Southern Phenomena [Anti-discrimination Actions], 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Mississippi (Including Medgar Evers), 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Black Power, White Power, Jewish Power,Italian, etc., circa 1963-1966, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Selma, Alabama, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Misc Politics, 1962-1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - [Brooklyn CORE Actions], 1961-1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - [Event Announcements, Newsletters, Correspondence, Programs, Clippings, etc.] (2 folders), 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - Clippings, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - [Clippings] (5 folders), 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 2-6)
  - [Clippings], 1963-1964, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - [Clippings and Other Documents], 1962-1964, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn CORE Newsletters (1 of 3), 1961-1965, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn CORE Newsletters (2 of 3), 1964 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn CORE Newsletters (3 of 3), 1963, 1983-2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - CORE - Letterhead, Business Cards, Etc., circa 1963 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Constitutions, By-Laws - Brooklyn CORE, Brooklyn College CORE, National CORE, circa 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - [CORE Sit-In Songs], 1962 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Freedom Songs, circa 1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - [CORE Chapter Chairmen and Offices], 1964 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - CORE Conventions - Minutes, Reports, Etc. and National Action Council Minutes, 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - CORE Literature and Reports, circa 1956-1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - In Freedom's Defense; Brooklyn Civil Rights Defense Committee Correspondence, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - [The Zealots - Pan-Semitic Brotherhood], circa 1964 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - RAM - Revolutionary Activity (Domestic), 1964-1967, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Alliance for Jobs or Income Now, circa 1965 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - [Letters to Editor re: Malcolm X], 1965 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Plots - Statue of Liberty, Wilkins-Young [Assassination], 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - SNCC Literature Etc., circa 1963-circa 1966 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Nuclear Weapons, Fallout, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - fACTs, ergo [Committee for Peace Organization], 1961-1965 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Peace, Disarmament, circa 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Dave Mitchell vs United States [Draft Resistance], 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Vietnam - Publications (From and About), 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Vietnam - Protests, Criticism, 1965-1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Vietnam - The War, Internal Opposition, US Statements, 1967-1968, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Rosenberg - Sobell Case, 1963-1967, 1975-1978, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - [Dick Gregory for President Handbills], 1968 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - [Brooklyn Committee in Defense of the Black Panthers - Statement], 1970 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - KCLR [Community Action Group], 1971 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Migrant Labor, Grape Pickers, Etc., Coal Miners, 1960-1965 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - [ Unconstitutional Conditions, The Property Rights of Indigents, and Equal Protection Analysis, paper by Alan R. Wolfson], 1974 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Africa, So. America, Etc., Apartheid, Colonialism, Revolution, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - [ Children's Rights Report, ACLU publication] (2 folders), 1976-1979 (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
  - [Request for Disclosure of Police Department Files], 1986, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - [Police Reports] Metropolitan Council on Housing, 1961-1971 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - [Police Reports] Goldwag, Arnold, 1962-1971 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - [Police Reports] Harlem Hospital, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - [Police Reports] Rockaway Council of Civic Associations, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - [Police Reports] East Harlem Triangle Civic Association (including CORE, Harlem Parents, Kinloch), 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - [Police Reports] Procept, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - [Police Reports] Harlem Parents Committee, 1963-1965, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - [Police Reports] CORE Brooklyn - Rent Strikes and Police HQ; CORE - General, 1963-1964, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - [Police Reports] School Boycott, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - [Police Reports] Mississippi Relief Committee, Mississippi-Alabama Southern Relief Committee, 1963, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - [Police Reports] Independent Community Improvement Association, 1963, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - [Police Reports] Hotel Industry - Discrimination, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - [Police Reports] Alliance for Jobs and Income Now, 1964-1968 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - [Police Reports] Police Brutality; Core and Brooklyn Freedom Democratic Movement, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - [Police Reports] Saul Alinsky, Clergy Concerned, Citywide [Committee for Emergency Services], 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - [Police Reports] SNCC, 1965, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - [Police Reports] Rent Control, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - [Police Reports] Peace and Freedom Party, United Farm Workers, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - [Police Reports] NYU - Washington Square, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - [Police Reports] Poor Peoples Campaign (ML King), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - [Police Reports] SDS [Columbia University Community Action Committee], 1968 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - [Police Reports] Wallace for President [Rally at Park Sheraton], 1968 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - [Police Reports] Vietnam / Hiroshima [Protest Demonstrations], 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - [Police Reports] Freedom and Peace Party, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - [Police Reports] Hiroshima Week, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - [Police Reports] Youth Against War and Facism, Anti Imperialism Rally, 1968, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - [Police Reports] Cambridge, MD - [Caravan for] Justice 4 Rap Brown (Freedom and Peace Party), 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - [Police Reports] Attica Prison Riot Protest - YAWF [Youth Against War and Fascism] and Others, 1971; Photocopies of photographs (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - [Police Reports] (2 folders), 1962-1969, undated (Box 8, Folder 27-28)
  - Arnie - Brooklyn College, 1956-1968 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - [ History and Analysis of Resistance to Military Conscription, 1863-1968, paper by Arnold Goldwag] (3 copies) (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
  - Notes and Source Material - Paper on History of the Draft - All Cases, Etc., Mitchell [includes photocopies of material dated circa 1917-1964] (3 folders), circa 1968 (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
  - The Metamorphosis of West African Religion and Culture in the Caribbean and the United States, paper by Arnold Goldwag, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Otis Gamm [Clippings from Kingsman, Brooklyn College], 1958-1961 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - People vs Goldwag - Subway, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Select Service and Army, 1961-1963, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - U.S. Post Office - Application, Papers, Transcripts, Etc., 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Violation of Probation, 1963-1964, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Appointment Books, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - [Goldwag Prison Term], 1964 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Rikers Island Penitentiary, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Personal - Correspondence (4 folders), 1962-1980s (Box 10, Folder 8-11)
  - [Correspondence], 1989, 1998-2005 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - [Miscellaneous Notes], circa 1964-circa 2000 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - [Keypunched Cards], undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 15 Crown [Realty], Crown St. Air Pollution, Crown Auto Laundry, 1966-1968 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Bushwick Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Cobble Hill [-Carroll Gardens Social Service Center], 1978-1981 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - [Major Owens], 1986-2002 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Marches, Demonstrations - Georgia, Wash DC, NY, Etc., 1963, 1983-2002 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Health, Vitamins, Etc., 1972-2005 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - House, Outdoors, Indoors, 1983-2003 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - First Annual Leadership Training Institute and Civil Rights Reunion (2 folders), 1990 (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
  - [First Annual Leadership Training Institute and Civil Rights Reunion], 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - [Isaiah House Brochure], circa 1990 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - [ Bloodlines, Publication of Rural Organizing and Cultural Center], 1988, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - [ Free at Last, Publication of Southern Poverty Law Center], 1989 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - [Freedom Riders Commemorative Conference], 1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - [ Appeal to this Age: Photography of the Civil Rights Movement, Exhibition Catalog], 1994 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - [CORE Reunions] (3 folders), 1989, 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 5-7)
  - [CORE Reunion and James Farmer Tribute - Member Contact Effort], 1962, 1966, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - [Miscellaneous Civil Rights Material], 1998, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - People I Know (2 folders), circa 1986-2003 (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
  - Death, Obits - CORE, Union, Etc., circa 1985-2004 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - [James Farmer Memorials], 1997, 1999, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - [Memorials and Tributes], 1988-1989, 2002, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - [ Long Walk to Freedom, Exhibition Pamphlet], 2001 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - [Historical Research Papers, Requests, and Proposals] (3 folders), 1985-2006 (Box 13, Folder 5-7)
    General note
    Includes research papers written by Brian J. Purnell concerning CORE actions.
  - [Clippings], 1983-2007 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - [Lapel Pins and Buttons - Elections, Anti-War, etc.] (2 boxes), circa 1960-circa 2000 (Box 14-15)
- Series 2: Books, 1943-1993; 6.5 Linear feet
  The container list is arranged in alphabetical order by author. The actual books are boxed in no particular order.
  The Books series includes published material from Arnie Goldwag's library. These are primarily non-fiction books and pamphlets concerning African-Americans, civil rights, race relations, racial violence, black militancy, social conditions, and related topics. A small number of books are inscribed to Goldwag by activists Kwane Ture (Stokely Carmichael), Jamil Al-Amin (H. Rap Brown), Dick Gregory, Gloria Richardson, and Conrad Lynn. There are a small number of issues of Landscapes and Nocturne, literary publications from Brooklyn College.
  - Addlestone, David F., Susan H. Hewman, et al., The Rights of Veterans, 1978 (Box 16, Item 1)
  - Adelman, Bob, Down Home: Camden, Alabama, 1972 (Box 20, Item 1)
  - AFSCME, Passing the Bucks, 1984 (Box 20, Item 2)
  - Al-Amin, Imam Jamil (H. Rap Brown), Revolution by the Book, 1993 (Box 20, Item 3)
    Inscribed by author
  - American Oil Company, American Travelers Guide to Negro Monuments, 1963 (Box 13, Item 1)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, A Citizen's Guide to the Right Wing, circa 1978 (Box 13, Item 2)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, Nat Turner's Slave Rebellion, 1968 (Box 16, Item 2)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, Heavenly Days in Dixie, or The Time of Their Lives, 1974 (Box 13, Item 3)
  - Bailey, F. Lee, The Defense Never Rests, 1972 (Box 19, Item 1)
  - Beck, Robert, The Naked Soul of Iceberg Slim, 1971 (Box 19, Item 2)
  - Belfrage, Sally, Freedom Summer, 1966 (Box 16, Item 3)
  - Bennett, Jr. Lerone, The Negro Mood, 1965 (Box 16, Item 4)
  - Bernard, Mitchell, Ellen Levine, et al., The Rights of Single People, 1985 (Box 16, Item 5)
  - Bettelheim, Bruno, Love is Not Enough, 1965 (Box 19, Item 3)
  - Bill Adler Books, The Wisdom of Martin Luther King, 1968 (Box 16, Item 6)
  - Birmingham, Stephen, The Right People, 1969 (Box 19, Item 4)
  - Blair, Jr. Clay, The Strange Case of James Earl Ray, 1969 (Box 16, Item 7)
  - Blaustein, Albert P.and Robert L. Zangrando, Civil Rights and the American Negro, 1968 (Box 16, Item 8)
  - Boggan, E. Carrington, Marilyn G. Haft, et al., The Rights of Gay People, 1983 (Box 16, Item 9)
  - Boggs, James, The American Revolution: Pages From a Negro Worker's Notebook, 1963 (Box 13, Item 4)
  - Branch, Taylor, Parting the Waters, 1988 (Box 17, Item 1)
  - Breitman, George (ed.), Malcolm X Speaks, 1966 (Box 16, Item 10)
  - Breitman, George (ed.), Malcolm X on Afro-American History, 1967 (Box 13, Item 5)
  - Brooklyn College, Landscapes Fall 58, 1958 (Box 13, Item 6)
  - Brooklyn College, Landscapes Spring 58, 1958 (Box 13, Item 7)
  - Brooklyn College, Landscapes Spring 59, 1959 (Box 13, Item 8)
  - Brooklyn College, Nocturne Spring 1963 (Box 13, Item 9)
  - Brooklyn College, Nocturne Spring 1967 (Box 13, Item 10)
  - Brown, Claude, The Children of Ham, 1976 (Box 18, Item 1)
  - Brown, Jr, Turner, Black Is, 1969 (Box 16, Item 11)
  - Carlson, John Roy, Under Cover, 1943 (Box 17, Item 2)
  - Carmichael, Stokely and Charles V. Hamilton, Black Power: The Politics of Liberation, 1967 (Box 19, Item 5)
  - Carroll, Ted, White Pills, 1964 (Box 17, Item 3)
  - Chapman, Abraham (ed.), Black Voices, 1968 (Box 20, Item 4)
  - Chrisman, Robert and Nathan Hare (ed.), Contemporary Black Thought, 1973 (Box 18, Item 2)
  - Clarke, John Henrik (ed.), Harlem: A Community in Transition, 1964 (Box 17, Item 4)
  - Cleaver, Eldridge, Soul on Ice, 1968 (Box 20, Item 5)
  - Cleaver, Eldridge, Post-Prison Writings and Speeches, 1969 (Box 20, Item 6)
  - Cohen, Jerry and William S. Murphy, Burn, Baby, Burn!, 1966 (Box 17, Item 5)
  - Collier, John, Indians of the Americas, circa 1960 (Box 16, Item 12)
  - Comer, James, Beyond Black and White, 1972 (Box 17, Item 6)
  - Corwin, Norman, Overkill and Megalove, 1963 (Box 18, Item 3)
  - Countdown Mag (ed.), Countdown 1, 1970 (Box 19, Item 6)
  - Dailey, Louis E., The Sin or Evils of Integration, 1962 (Box 18, Item 4)
  - deCoy, Robert H., The Nigger Bible, 1967 (Box 19, Item 7)
  - Dorman, Michael, We Shall Overcome, 1965 (Box 16, Item 13)
  - Dorson, Richard M. (ed.), American Negro Folktales, 1967 (Box 19, Item 8)
  - Douglas, William O., America Challenged, 1960 (Box 19, Item 9)
  - Douglas, William O., The Right of the People, 1962 (Box 19, Item 10)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B., John Brown, 1962 (Box 19, Item 11)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B., An A.B.C. of Color, 1963 (Box 19, Item 12)
  - Fanon, Frantz, Black Skin, White Masks, 1968 (Box 16, Item 14)
  - Fanon, Frantz, The Wretched of the Earth, 1968 (Box 16, Item 15)
  - Feldmann, Susan (ed.), African Myths and Tales, 1963 (Box 19, Item 13)
  - Franklin, John Hope (intro), 3 Negro Classics: Up from Slavery [Washington]; The Souls of Black Folk [Du Bois]; The Autobiography of an Ex-Colored Man [Johnson], 1965 (Box 19, Item 14)
  - Free, Revolution for the Hell of It, 1968 (Box 20, Item 7)
  - Friedman, Paul R., The Rights of Mentally Retarded Persons, 1976 (Box 19, Item 15)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth, The Liberal Hour, 1964 (Box 19, Item 16)
  - Gardner, John W., In Common Cause, 1973 (Box 18, Item 5)
  - Gary, Romain, White Dog, 1970 (Box 17, Item 7)
  - Ginzburg, Ralph, 100 Years of Lynchings, 1969 (Box 16, Item 16)
  - Gitlin, Todd, The Sixties: Years of Hope, Days of Rage, 1987 (Box 18, Item 6)
  - Glazer, Nathan and Daniel Patrick Moynihan, Beyond the Melting Pot, 1967 (Box 18, Item 7)
  - Goodman, Mary Ellen, Race Awareness in Young Children, 1964 (Box 16, Item 17)
  - Goodman, Paul (ed.), Seeds of Liberation, 1964 (Box 17, Item 8)
  - Gover, Robert, Here Goes Kitten, 1964 (Box 18, Item 8)
  - Grant, Joanne (ed.), Black Protest, 1968 (Box 19, Item 17)
  - Gregory, Dick, Nigger: An Autobiography, 1965 (Box 20, Item 8)
    Inscribed by author.
  - Gregory, Dick, The Shadow That Scares Me, 1968 (Box 16, Item 18)
  - Gregory, Dick, Write Me In!, 1968 (Box 20, Item 9)
  - Grier, William H. and Price M. Cobbs, Black Rage, 1968 (Box 20, Item 10)
  - Griffin, John Howard, Black Like Me, 1962 (Box 16, Item 19)
  - Guevara, Che, Guerrilla Warfare, 1961 (Box 16, Item 20)
  - Guggenheim, Martin and Alan Sussman, The Rights of Young People, 1985 (Box 16, Item 21)
  - Haley, Alex, Roots, 1976 (Box 17, Item 9)
  - Halsell, Grace, Soul Sister, 1970 (Box 16, Item 10)
  - Hentoff, Nat, The New Equality, 1965 (Box 18, Item 9)
  - Hernton, Calvin C., Sex and Racism in America, 1966 (Box 19, Item 18)
  - Herrick, Arnold and Herbert Askwith (ed.), This Way to Unity, 1945 (Box 18, Item 10)
  - Hersey, John, The Algiers Motel Incident, 1968 (Box 16, Item 11)
  - Hirschfield, Robert S., The Constitution and The Court, 1965 (Box 19, Item 12)
  - Holmes, Beth, The Whipping Boy, 1979 (Box 16, Item 13)
  - Hughes, Langston (ed.), The Best Short Stories by Negro Writers, 1967 (Box 20, Item 11)
  - Huie, William Bradford, 3 Lives for Mississippi, 1965 (Box 18, Item 11)
  - Huie, William Bradford, The Hiroshima Pilot, 1965 (Box 19, Item 12)
  - Hunter, John Francis, The Gay Insider/USA, 1972 (Box 18, Item 12)
  - Hunter, Kristin, The Landlord, 1969 (Box 19, Item 13)
  - Jackson, George, Soledad Brother: The Prison Letters of George Jackson, 1970 (Box 16, Item 14)
  - James, Beauregard, The Road to Birmingham, 1964 (Box 17, Item 10)
  - John Birch Society, The Blue Book of the John Birch Society, 1961 (Box 20, Item 12)
  - Joseph, Stephen M. (ed.), The Me Nobody Knows, 1969 (Box 16, Item 13)
  - Kelly, Philip J., How to Grow Old Rebelliously, 1963 (Box 18, Item 13)
  - Killens, John Oliver, The Cotillion, 1971 (Box 20, Item 13)
  - Killian, Lewis and Charles Grigg, Racial Crisis in America, 1964 (Box 20, Item 14)
  - Kohl, Herbert, 36 Children, 1968 (Box 16, Item 15)
  - Kozol, Jonathan, Death at an Early Age, 1968 (Box 16, Item 16)
  - Lanternari, Vittorio, The Religions of the Oppressed, 1965 (Box 19, Item 17)
  - Lavan, George (ed.), Che Guevara Speaks, 1968 (Box 16, Item 18)
  - Lederer, William J., A Nation of Sheep, 1962 (Box 19, Item 19)
  - Leinwand, Gerald, Problems of American Society: The Negro in the City, 1968 (Box 19, Item 20)
  - Leinwand, Gerald, Problems of American Society: Poverty and the Poor, 1968 (Box 19, Item 21)
  - Leinwand, Gerald, Problems of American Society: Crime and Juvenile Delinquency, 1968 (Box 19, Item 22)
  - Leinwand, Gerald, Problems of American Society: The Slums, 1970 (Box 19, Item 23)
  - Lester, Julius, Look Out, Whitey! Black Power's Gon' Get Your Mama, 1969 (Box 16, Item 24)
  - Levine, Roy, The New Apology, 1960 (Box 13, Item 11)
  - Lewis, Anthony, Gideon's Trumpet, 1964 (Box 19, Item 12)
  - Lewis, Oscar, Five Families, 1959 (Box 16, Item 13)
  - Lewis, Oscar, La Vida, 1968 (Box 18, Item 14)
  - Lipsyte, Robert, The Contender, 1969 (Box 19, Item 15)
  - Lomax, John A. and Alan Lomax, Folk Song U.S.A., 1966 (Box 20, Item 15)
  - Lomax, Louis E., When the Word is Given..., 1963 (Box 18, Item 15)
  - Ludwig, Bernard, Problems of American Society: Civil Rights and Civil Liberties, 1968 (Box 19, Item 16)
  - Lynn, Conrad J., How to Stay Out of the Army, 1967 (Box 20, Item 16)
  - Lyon, Danny, Memories of the Southern Civil Rights Movement, 1992 (Box 20, Item 17)
    Inscription on page 136 by Gloria Richardson.
  - Maas, Peter, The Valachi Papers, 1969 (Box 16, Item 18)
  - Malcolm X, The Autobiography of Malcolm X, 1965 (Box 18, Item 16)
  - Marshall, Paule, Soul Clap Hands and Sing, 1961 (Box 18, Item 17)
  - Marshall, Paule, Brown Girl, Brownstones, 1970 (Box 19, Item 18)
  - Marwick, Christine M., Your Right to Government Information, 1985 (Box 16, Item 19)
  - Meier, August and Elliot Rudwick, CORE: A Study in the Civil Rights Movement, 1942-1968, 1975 (Box 20, Item 18)
  - Milbauer, Barbara and Gerald Leinwand, Problems of American Society: Drugs, 1970 (Box 19, Item 19)
  - Mills, C. Wright, The Causes of World War Three, 1961 (Box 19, Item 20)
  - Monte, Anita and Gerald Leinwand, Problems of American Society: Riots, 1970 (Box 19, Item 21)
  - Moody, Anne, Coming of Age in Mississippi, 1968 (Box 18, Item 18)
  - Moon, Bucklin, The Darker Brother, 1943 (Box 18, Item 19)
  - N.Y. Committee to Free Angela Davis (ed.), Lectures on Liberation by Angela Y. Davis, circa 1970 (Box 13, Item 12)
  - National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders, Report of the National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders, 1968 (Box 19, Item 13)
  - National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence, To Establish Justice, To Insure Domestic Tranquility, 1971 (Box 17, Item 11)
  - Nelson, Truman, The Torture of Mothers, 1964 (Box 19, Item 12)
  - Neuborne, Burt and Arthur Eisenberg, The Rights of Candidates and Voters, 1980 (Box 16, Item 13)
  - Norfleet, Marvin Brooks, Forced School Integration in the U.S.A., 1961 (Box 18, Item 14)
  - Norwick, Kenneth P. and Jerry Simon Chasen, The Rights of Authors and Artists, 1984 (Box 16, Item 15)
  - O'Neill, William L. (ed.), Echoes of Revolt: The Masses, 1911-1917, 1966 (Box 20, Item 19)
  - Orben, Bob (ed.), Dick Gregory: From the Back of the Bus, 1966 (Box 20, Item 20)
  - Outten, Wayne N. and Noah A. Kinigstein, The Rights of Employees, 1984 (Box 16, Item 21)
  - Pevar, Stephen L., The Rights of Indians and Tribes, 1983 (Box 16, Item 22)
  - Pioneer Publishers (ed.), Two Speeches by Malcolm X, 1965 (Box 13, Item 13)
  - Rainwater, Lee, Behind Ghetto Walls, 1970 (Box 18, Item 14)
  - Randall, Dudley and Margaret G. Burroughs, For Malcolm X, 1967 (Box 18, Item 15)
  - Reeves, Ambrose, Shooting at Sharpeville, 1961 (Box 18, Item 16)
  - Ritter, Bruce, Sometimes God Has a Kid's Face, 1988 (Box 19, Item 17)
  - Robertson, John A., The Rights of the Critically Ill, 1983 (Box 16, Item 18)
  - Rogers, J.A., From "Superman" to Man, 1953 (Box 18, Item 19)
  - Rogers, J.A., 100 Amazing Facts about the Negro, 1957 (Box 13, Item 14)
  - Rosengarten, Theodore, All God's Dangers: The Life of Nate Shaw, 1975 (Box 16, Item 15)
  - Ross, Susan Deller and Ann Barcher, The Rights of Women, 1983 (Box 16, Item 16)
  - Roth, Philip, Our Gang, 1973 (Box 19, Item 17)
  - Rubin, David and Steven Greenhouse, The Rights of Teachers, 1984 (Box 16, Item 18)
  - Rubin, Jerry, Do It!, 1970 (Box 20, Item 21)
  - Ruchames, Louis (ed.), A John Brown Reader, undated (Box 17, Item 12)
  - Scheer, Robert (ed.), The Diary of Che Guevara, 1968 (Box 16, Item 13)
  - Schneir, Miriam (ed.), Feminism: The Essential Historical Writings, 1972 (Box 19, Item 14)
  - Schulman, L. M. (ed.), Come Out the Wilderness, 1965 (Box 16, Item 15)
  - Seale, Bobby, Seize the Time, 1970 (Box 16, Item 16)
  - Sforza, Count Carlo (ed.), The Living Thoughts of Machiavelli, 1958 (Box 19, Item 17)
  - Slim, Iceberg, Mama Black Widow, 1969 (Box 19, Item 18)
  - Smith, Edgar, Brief Against Death, 1969 (Box 19, Item 19)
  - Smith, Edgar, A Reasonable Doubt, 1971 (Box 16, Item 20)
  - Smith, Huston, The Religions of Man, 1963 (Box 19, Item 21)
  - Smith, Lillian, Strange Fruit, 1944 (Box 19, Item 22)
  - Smith, Lillian, Killers of the Dream, 1961 (Box 17, Item 13)
  - Southern Labor Institute, Now Is the Time, 1986 (Box 13, Item 15)
  - Stahl, David, Frederick B. Sussman, et al., The Community and Racial Crises, 1966 (Box 20, Item 22)
  - Stang, Alan, It's Very Simple, 1965 (Box 19, Item 23)
  - Stark, James and Howard W. Goldstein, The Rights of Crime Victims, 1985 (Box 16, Item 24)
  - Stearn, Jess, Sisters of the Night, 1956 (Box 18, Item 25)
  - Sterling, Philip (ed.), Laughing on the Outside, 1965 (Box 17, Item 14)